<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>the neural bit</title>
    <link>http://theneuralbit.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on the neural bit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>true</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://theneuralbit.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Poor Man&#39;s Threading (in Javascript)</title>
      <link>http://theneuralbit.com/blog/poor-mans-threading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theneuralbit.com/blog/poor-mans-threading/</guid>
      <description>Javascript is single-threaded.
I hear that all the time, but I think people&amp;rsquo;s interpretation of it is often an oversimplification. That statement is true within a single browser tab, but there are plenty of ways to get that browser to thread for you:
 Asynchronous I/O (AJAX or FileReader). The browser handles all the details of this for you, but at the end of the day it&amp;rsquo;s doing some kind of multi-threading to handle the request, so your browser tab can do other work in the meantime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun with git stash</title>
      <link>http://theneuralbit.com/blog/fun-with-git-stash/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theneuralbit.com/blog/fun-with-git-stash/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re anything like me, the only times you&amp;rsquo;ve ever used git stash it went something like this: In the middle of working on branch A you decided you should test something out on branch B. So you quickly run git stash, checkout branch B and test something, then come back to branch A, run git stash apply and pick back up where you left off.
Well it turns out git stash is much more powerful than that, and we&amp;rsquo;ve all been missing out for years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anagranimation</title>
      <link>http://theneuralbit.com/blog/anagranimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theneuralbit.com/blog/anagranimation/</guid>
      <description>The name of this website is an anagram. It&amp;rsquo;s possible to rearrange all of the letters in the neural bit to form brian hulette. That&amp;rsquo;s a simple concept I set out to illustrate concisely with the site&amp;rsquo;s logo.
For the first iteration of this webpage, way back when I was in late high school and early college (ca. 2007), I just pulled up the Gimp, which I had probably learned to use just the previous week, and drew up the following image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M.Eng. Project - Simulation of Configurable Filter Banks Directed by a Cyclostationary Detector</title>
      <link>http://theneuralbit.com/blog/meng-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theneuralbit.com/blog/meng-project/</guid>
      <description>theneuralbit/cyclo_channelizer  !embedlycard</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My LaTeX Development Environment</title>
      <link>http://theneuralbit.com/blog/latex-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theneuralbit.com/blog/latex-environment/</guid>
      <description>[gist:id=5b29004bd08cb23565d9,file=inotifyexec.sh]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing the Viterbi Algorithm</title>
      <link>http://theneuralbit.com/blog/viterbi-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theneuralbit.com/blog/viterbi-analysis/</guid>
      <description>This summer I am taking CS5114 - Theory of Algorithms at Virginia Tech. Our first Project was to analyze a Dynamic Programming algorithm, and compare it to other approaches that solve the same problem. Since I am focusing on DSP/Communications, I decided to look at the Viterbi algorithm, a Dynamic Programming approach to decoding Convolutional Codes.
For the project I investigated why the Viterbi algorithm is so much more efficient than alternative approaches to decoding convolutional codes (Such as a brute force or recursive technique).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This website</title>
      <link>http://theneuralbit.com/blog/this-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theneuralbit.com/blog/this-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This site was adapted from my old, static HTML website.
I wrote the original site way back in high school (with many updates throughout
college), and it was beginning to show its age.  The biggest issue was that I
didn&amp;rsquo;t create it with any sort of templating to begin with, so when I wanted to
update the appearance, my changes had to be manually propogated to every page.
Enter &lt;a href=&#34;http://jekyllrb.com/&#34;&gt;jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://octopress.org&#34;&gt;octopress&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comfortably Numb Solo Synthesis</title>
      <link>http://theneuralbit.com/blog/comfortably-numb-synth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2011 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theneuralbit.com/blog/comfortably-numb-synth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During my last quarter at Rose-Hulman I took a great class called ECE481 -
Electronic Music Synthesis.  In it, we discussed a lot of concepts used to
synthesize music, including additive and destructive synthesis, FM synthesis,
the Karplus-Strong algorithm, and various post-processing and mixing techniques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a final project for the course we were asked to create a song using some of
the techniques we learned about.  For my project, I chose to synthesize the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Bpzxf_flm8M#t=04m25s&#34;&gt;solo&lt;/a&gt; from the Pink Floyd
song &amp;ldquo;Comfortably Numb&amp;rdquo; using the Karplus-Strong Algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-Altitude Imaging</title>
      <link>http://theneuralbit.com/blog/high-altitude-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2010 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theneuralbit.com/blog/high-altitude-imaging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the spring of 2010 my brother and I decided we would like to launch a camera
into near-space, in order to take images of the earth from 90,000+ feet.  We
were primarily inspired by a well known project completed by some MIT students
called &lt;a href=&#34;http://space.1337arts.com&#34;&gt;Project Icarus&lt;/a&gt;. They became somewhat famous
in the fall of 2009 by launching their vehicle into the stratosphere for less
than $150. We have also utilized resources from the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ukhas.org.uk&#34;&gt;UK High-Altitude Society&lt;/a&gt; for various information regarding
this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timelapse Photography</title>
      <link>http://theneuralbit.com/blog/timelapse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2010 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theneuralbit.com/blog/timelapse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently acquired a Canon PowerShot A530 camera, and decided to use it to take
a few timelapse videos. I installed the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://chdk.wikia.com/wiki/CHDK&#34;&gt;Canon Hardware Development Kit (CHDK)&lt;/a&gt; on it,
which gives me a lot more control over the camera&amp;rsquo;s settings. You
can use it to write scripts to automatically control the camera.  I used
&lt;a href=&#34;http://chdk.wikia.com/wiki/UBASIC/Scripts:_Ultra_Intervalometer&#34;&gt;this simple script&lt;/a&gt; to
capture the pictures for these timelapses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LED Audio Visualizer</title>
      <link>http://theneuralbit.com/blog/led-audio-visualizer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2010 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theneuralbit.com/blog/led-audio-visualizer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;{filename}/images/led_visualizer.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Completed LED Visualizer&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my Embedded Systems Design class, we were required to create a final project
of our choosing which demonstrated our understanding of the course concepts. My
partner and I decided to create an Audio Visualizer for our final project. The
idea was to display the audio spectrum in real-time (calculated with an FFT) on
an LED Matrix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carputer</title>
      <link>http://theneuralbit.com/blog/carputer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2009 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theneuralbit.com/blog/carputer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months after I got my new Volvo S70, I began to think that the stereo
head unit would be perfect for a carputer (car computer). It&amp;rsquo;s a rather large
head unit, probably about twice as tall as a typical one, so there would be
plenty of space inside for a computer and the other necessary electronics. The
other great thing about it is that you can remove it just by popping two tabs
and pulling it out, making debugging really easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predator-Prey Simulation</title>
      <link>http://theneuralbit.com/blog/predator-prey-sim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2009 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theneuralbit.com/blog/predator-prey-sim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project was inspired by two classes that I took.  The first was
Introduction to Complex Systems, which I took my senior year in high school. It
was a sort of review of a lot of interesting high level math concepts, we spent
a while talking about &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fractal&#34;&gt;fractals&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mandelbrot_set&#34;&gt;the mandelbrot set&lt;/a&gt;, and then
moved on to what really interested me, cellular automata.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea of cellular automata is to make a lot of little cells that follow some
relatively simple rules, but when you watch their overall behavior over a lot of
iterations some interesting patterns form. The most famous example is
&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/conway&#39;s_game_of_life&#34;&gt;conway&amp;rsquo;s game of life&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second class, which I took my freshman year of college was Differential
Equations 2. In this class we modeled a lot of random things t demostrate
differential equations and one such model was the populations of predators and
prey living in the same area. If you fiddle with the constants in the model just
right you can end up with two sinusoidal populations with the prey wave lagging
the predator wave a little bit. The idea is that when there are a lot of
predators, they kill off the prey, but when the prey populations gets so low,
the predators begin to starve, so the prey have time to reproduce and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So one day in DE2 I began to drift off and came up with the idea of making a
predator prey simulation using cellular automata, and this is the result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stack Processor utnik (S.P.utnik)</title>
      <link>http://theneuralbit.com/blog/sputnik/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2009 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theneuralbit.com/blog/sputnik/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During Fall quarter of my Sophomore year at Rose I took Computer Architecture.
For most of the quarter, the class is assigned to design a 16-bit processor in
teams of 4. These are the results of that project for my group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clock in a Book</title>
      <link>http://theneuralbit.com/blog/clockbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2009 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theneuralbit.com/blog/clockbook/</guid>
      <description>Over the summer I needed an amplifier for my TV visualizer. I bought a kit for one online, but the site I bought it from had a minimum purchase price, so I decided to buy a led clock kit to go with it. Once I had the clock all soldered up, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find anything to put it in. Then I realized that I could use the same technique I used for my hollow book to cut slots in a book for the clock components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hollow Book</title>
      <link>http://theneuralbit.com/blog/hollowbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2009 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://theneuralbit.com/blog/hollowbook/</guid>
      <description>My senior year of high school, my roommate and I stumbled on [this tutorial][http://www.wikihow.com/Make-a-Hollow-Book] on making a hollow book. We decided it would be pretty cool to have one, so I pulled a book that I had already read off the shelf and we got to work. We finished cutting it up and gluing it that same night.
At first we used it to store our contraband - Nothing really bad, our high school didn&amp;rsquo;t let us keep things like matches or extension cords in our rooms, which we thought was ridiculous.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>